Brian Miner

React / Next.js Developer

brian-miner.vercel.app | www.linkedin.com/in/brian-miner | bminer85@gmail.com | +57 322-509-0179 |

PROFILE

Seeking opportunities as a React/Next.js web developer after transitioning from a 12-year career in petroleum engineering. I am an extremely disciplined and dedicated developer and have built several full-stack applications utilizing JavaScript / Typescript, React / Next.js, Express.js and Node.js technologies.

SKILLS

HTML
JavaScript / TypeScript
CSS / Tailwind CSS / Bootstrap

React.js / Next.js NextAuth / Passport.js Context / Redux / Zustand Python
Express JS / Node.js
MongoDB / Firebase

PROJECTS

Coffee Evaluation App | Express, Node.js, MongoDB / Passport.js Authentication

- Developed a server-side rendered application using Express, Node.js and MongoDB for coffee professionals to assess coffees based on international Specialty Coffee Association (SCA) standards.
- The app can enhance QA/QC practices along the coffee chain from purchasing, import and export, to roasting and retail, while also lowering a user's carbon-footprint by eliminating the need for physical paper forms.
- I implemented secure user authentication via Passport.js and safeguard data with salted and hashed credentials stored in MongoDB.
- The front-end is styled using plain CSS and Bootstrap, while HTML is rendered with EJS templates.

Trello Clone | React.js / Next.js / Appwrite / ChatGPT-3

- Created a fully functioning single-page application (SPA) Trello clone with drag and drop task boards.
- The application is built using React.js / Next.js technologies, leveraging Zustand for streamlined state management.
- A simplified ChatGPT-3 bot was integrated from OpenAl API to summarize the tasks across each task board.

Netflix Clone | React.js / Firebase / Stripe / Firebase Authentication

- Developed a beautiful Netflix clone using React components and mimics a typical user experience including multitier subscriptions and a fully functional Stripe payment portal.
- Authentication, subscription tiers and payments are connected to a Firebase database.

IN PROGRESS

Teacher Reporting App | React.js / Next.js / MongoDB / NextAuth

- Currently building a teacher portal for Profesores Extranjeros using React.js / Next.js and MongoDB to facilitate end of month reporting.
- The application aims to eliminate inefficient and inconsistent internal reports and enhance client relations by providing a standardized and user-friendly experience.
- Implementing NextAuth for teacher login/authentication and an intuitive dashboard to view/update class schedules and student rosters while providing access to previous reports and

Resume Builder | React.js / Next.js / MongoDB / ChatGPT-3

- Currently developing a resume generation app to reinforce skills learned during the Trello Build and to help jobseekers build effortless resumes to aid in the job-hunting process.
- The application will be built using React.js / Next.js and MongoDB with ChatGPT and Grammarly integration for real-time writing suggestions and to improve user writing style.

The page layout will be built using drag and drop sections allowing for quick and easy resume styling.

Nutrition & Fitness App | React.js / Next.js / MongoDB

- Designing a personal fitness and calorie tracking application inspired by a self-built Excel spreadsheet that led to a personal weight loss of over 30 lbs.
- The application will connect with MongoDB enabling users to choose from and update a personalized food list along with serving sizes, calorie counts and macro-nutrient tracking.
- The responsive front-end is being built with React.js and will include a dashboard of essential metrics such as BMR, calories burned vs calories consumed and calorie/macro goals to align diet strategy with user fitness goals.

COURSES

React – The Complete Guide 2023

Academind – Maximilian Schwarzmüller

Docker Mastery: with Kubernetes + Swarm

Udemy – Bret Fisher (Docker Captain)

MongoDB – Complete Developer's Guide 2023

Academind - Maximilian Schwarzmüller

Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp

London's App Brewery – Dr. Angela Yu

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

English Teacher (TEFL) | Professor's Extranjeros – Medellín, Colombia

Mar 2021 – Present

• Provide English instruction for corporations & individuals covering a variety of needs from Exam Prep to Client Engagement and Career Advancement

Staff Production Engineer | Chesapeake Energy – Oklahoma City, OK Dec 2014 – Sep 2020

- Responsible for well production rates in the High-Pressure/High-Temperature Haynesville Shale overseeing all
 aspects of well-surveillance, remediation, and production optimization.
- Led a cross-functional team to research and execute on a novel production strategy which delivered \$4MM in additional free-cash-flow to the asset for fiscal year 2020.
- Developed and applied flow assurance and artificial lift models, elevating new well IP by 14% and reducing monthly OPEX by \$20K.
- Mentored 5 summer interns, providing technical guidance, all of whom received full-time offers from the company.

Production Engineer | BP - Amarillo, TX

Dec 2012 - Dec 2014

- Managed production for 300+ low-pressure unconventional wells in the Anadarko Basin.
- Designed and implemented a plunger-lift optimization model that boosted plunger install success by 15%, reduced non-arrival events by 30% and significantly improved field cash-flow while reducing workover related OPEX.

EDUCATION

University of Oklahoma | Norman, OK

- Master's Petroleum Engineering......May 2013
- Bachelor's Chemical Engineering......May 2010

LANGUAGES